Guide to the Martin Bronfenbrenner Papers, 1939-1995 and undated RL.00153
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Martin Bronfenbrenner papers
1939-1995 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bronfenbrenner, Martin, 1914-1997
RL.00153
16.2 Linear Feet
Economist on the faculty at Duke University. The professional papers of Martin Bronfenbrenner span the years 1939 to 1995 and consist of correspondence, research files, memoranda, writings (published and unpublished), teaching materials, reprints, clippings, and other papers, relating chiefly to Bronfenbrenner's research and associations in the field of economics. Topics in his research files, which make up the bulk of the collection, include income distribution theory, economic development, Marxian and radical economics (including New Left economics), labor economics, monetary economics, international economics, trade, Japanese economy and Japanese history. The collection is organized into the following series: Personal Files, Printed Material, Research and Writing Files, and Teaching Material.
Approximately 12,000 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Martin Bronfenbrenner Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1984, 1993, and 1997.
Biographical Note
Martin Bronfenbrenner was born in Pittsburgh in 1914 and died in 1997 in Durham, North Carolina, having just been made a Distinguished Fellow of the American Economics Association. He received his Ph.D. in 1939 from the Universtiy of Chicago and after a brief stint at the U.S. Treasury, enlisted in the U.S. Navy. He served in Japan during and after the war, and had a role in the rebuilding of Japan's economy and its relations with the U.S. Taking from his experiences in Japan, Bronfenbrenner published a volume of fictional short stories entitled Tomioka Stories from the Japanese Occupation. From 1947 on, Bronfenbrenner worked exclusively as a university professor. He served on the faculty of the University of Wisconsin (1947-1957), Michigan State University (1957-1958), the University of Minnesota (1958-1962), Carnegie Mellon (1962-1971), and Duke University where he held the Kenan Chair from 1971 until 1984. In 1984, he moved to Japan as a professor of international economics at the Aoyama Gakuin University in Tokyo, Japan, and in 1991 he returned to Duke University where he taught until his death in 1997. Throughout this period Bronfenbrenner's interests were very wide-ranging and included income distribution theory, labor economics, Marxian and radical economics, development, Japanese economics and history, comparative economic systems, monetary theory and the history of economics. Bronfenbrenner served as vice-president of the American Economic Association (1976-1977), president of the Southern Economic Association (1979-1980), and president of the History of Economics Society (1982-1983).
Collection Overview
The professional papers of Martin Bronfenbrenner span the years 1939 to 1995 and consist of correspondence, research files, memoranda, writings (published and unpublished), teaching materials, reprints, clippings, and other papers, relating chiefly to Bronfenbrenner's research and associations in the field of economics. The collection is organized into the following series: Personal Files, Published Material, Research and Writing Files, and Teaching Material. The Personal Papers Series includes an unpublished autobiography, a family history, and records of Bronfenbrenner's own U.S. loyalty hearings from 1954-1955. Files in the Teaching Material Series chiefly contain syllabi, course notes, and exams dating from Bronfenbrenner's time at Carnegie, Duke, and in Japan, while the Printed Material files mainly house reprints of many of his articles. The Research Files Series, divided into topical subseries, makes up the bulk of the collection, including Bronfenbrenner's research notes, articles, reprints, correspondence, lectures, and drafts of Bronfenbrenner's writings; the materials offer a rich source of unique research material on topics of interest to Bronfenbrenner such as income distribution theory, economic development, Marxian and radical economics (including New Left economics), labor economics, monetary economics, international economics, trade, Japanese economy and Japanese history. The Research Files also contains a subseries of research folders linked to individual economists in whose work Bronfenbrenner had an interest, or with whom he corresponded, or both; names include Adelman, Baumol, Friedman, Leijonhufvud, Minsky, Samuelson, Spengler, Solow, and Viner, with two folders of material on Kei Shibata, who wrote on Marxian economics and economic equilibrium during the 1930s.
United States -- Politics and government -- 1953-1961; Income distribution; Friedman, Milton, 1912-2006; International trade; Inflation (Finance); Economics -- History -- 20th century; Economists -- Correspondence; Economists -- United States; Economics -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; China -- Economic conditions; Chicago School of Economics; Demand for money; Labor economics; Japan -- History; Japan -- Economic conditions; International economic relations; Monetary policy; Marxian economics; Macroeconomics; Loyalty oaths -- United States; United States -- Foreign economic relations -- Japan; United States -- Economic conditions; Unemployment -- Effect of inflation on; Theory of distributions (Functional analysis); Clippings (information artifacts); Adelman, Morris Albert; Viner, Jacob, 1892-1970; Spengler, Joseph J. (Joseph John), 1902-1991; Leijonhufvud, Axel; Minsky, Hyman P.; Samuelson, Paul A. (Paul Anthony), 1915-2009; Solow, Robert M.; Baumol, William J.; Bronfenbrenner family; Bronfenbrenner, Martin, 1914-1997
- Personal Files Series, 1939-1983 and undated, 2 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains files maintained by Bronfenbrenner which include his unpublished dissertation, curriculum vitae, family correspondence, personal office files, and a family history and family tree from 1977. There are two folders dedicated to Bronfenbrenner's loyalty hearings in 1954 to 1955 when Bronfenbrenner's commitment to the United States was publicly questioned as was his interest in Marxian economics. There is one folder of short humorous poems written by Bronfenbrenner throughout his career, often using the pseudonym "The Beardless Beatnik." Bronfenbrenner's unpublished autobiography is also included in this series.
  - Correspondence, 1972-1983 (Box 1)
  - Doctoral thesis, Monetary theory and general equilibrium, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Family history, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Loyalty hearing, 1954-1955, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Personal office files, 1971-1983, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Curriculum vitae, 1977-1982, undated (Box 2)
  - Scurrilous verse, undated (Box 2)
  - Unpublished autobiography, undated (Box 2)
- Printed Material Series, 1939-1995, 4 boxes
  Chiefly contains offprints of journal articles and journal issues containing articles by Brofenbrenner. Additionally, there are individual copies of Bronfenbrenner's collection of short stories Tomioko Stories, recalling Bronfenbrenner's time in Japan when it was under American occupation, as well as Is the Business Cycle Obsolete?, edited by Bronfenbrenner. The contents of the boxes are arranged in date order.
  - Bronfenbrenner reprints and publications (Box 2-5)
- Research Files Series, 1939-1995, 18 boxes
  Representing the main component of the Bronfenbrenner Papers, the series is subdivided into the following subseries: Development, Heterodox Topics, Income Distribution, Orthodox Topics, People, and Japan.
  - Development Subseries, 1954-1990, 2 boxes
    Folders house materials relating to one of Bronfenbrenner's ongoing interests, economic development, focused mainly on developing Asian countries or regions. The files contains notes, speeches, draft and published papers written by Bronfenbrenner, papers written by other authors relevant to Bronfenbrenner's research, relevant correspondence, newspaper articles, and other miscellaneous documents. Arranged alphabetically by original folder title.
    - China after Mao, 1982-1983 (Box 5)
    - Committee for Economic Development: productivity, 1981 (Box 5)
    - Development programming, Malaysia, 1969-1973 (Box 5)
    - Development profiles: hard and soft development, 1963-1967 (Box 5)
    - Exports and foreign capital, 1968, 1979 (Box 5)
    - IEA international conference in Tokyo, 1977 (Box 5)
    - Indian sub-continent, 1961 (Box 5)
    - Indo-China, 1954, 1965 (Box 5)
    - Indonesia, 1962 (Box 5)
    - Korea, 1963, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Mahalanobis model, 1960-1962, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - NIEO, 1976-1978 (Box 5)
    - Notes on foreign aid, 1957 (Box 5)
    - Riots and hunger, 1968-1969 (Box 6)
    - Slobbovia meets the market, 1990 (Box 6)
    - Taiwan, 1969-72 (Box 6)
    - Turkey, 1978-1981 (Box 6)
    - The terms of convergence, 1982 (Box 6)
    - UNESCO paper, 1975 (Box 6)
    - United Nations Conference on Trade and Development (UNCTAD): Dependency, 1976-1977 (Box 6)
    - USSR: general impressions, 1972, 1975 (Box 6)
    - U.S.-USSR relations, 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Heterodox Topics Subseries, 1953-1991 and undated, 5 boxes
    Bronfenbrenner conducted research, wrote papers and corresponded on topics which fell outside the range of traditional economic subject areas. In particular, Bronfenbrenner had a career-long interest in the work of Marx, Marxian economics, and radical political economy. While always critical of these approaches to economics, he was a strong proponent of academic freedom and respected Marxist approaches to economic analysis. Other topics include anti-Semitism, Reagonomics, black economics, futurology, and social responsibility. The folders contain notes, speeches, draft and published papers written by Bronfenbrenner, papers written by other authors relevant to Bronfenbrenner's research, correspondence, newspaper articles, and other miscellaneous papers. Ordered alphabetically by original folder title.
    - Alienation, 1971-1973 (Box 6)
    - Anti-economics, 1965, 1972 (Box 6)
    - The anti-semite Jew, a useful citizen?, 1966 (Box 6)
    - Appeal of confiscation, 1966, undated (Box 6)
    - Baran paper: Academic freedom, 1965-1971, undated (Box 6)
    - Black economics, 1971 (Box 6)
    - A Calculus Suicide, 1977 (Box 6)
    - Comparative systems, 1972-1979 (Box 6)
    - Cooperative democracy: decentralized workers' management, 1969 (Box 6)
    - College of H and SS, 1968-1969 (Box 6)
    - Disarmament, 1961-1963 (Box 7)
    - Do economists matter?, 1975 (Box 7)
    - Economics as dentistry, 1991 (Box 7)
    - Economics in the near future, 1989 (Box 7)
    - Futurology, 1973-1978 (Box 7)
    - Hollis and Nell: methodology review, 1975-1977 (Box 7)
    - Institutional economics, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Labour front, undated (Box 7)
    - MacArthur memorial, 1976-1978, undated (Box 7)
    - Marriage market as a market, 1971-1973 (Box 7)
    - Marxist capital consumption ratio, 1966-1968 (Box 7)
    - Marxian distribution theory, undated (Box 7)
    - Marxian economics, 1963-1971, 1974, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - McCarthyism, 1953-1962 (Box 7)
    - Meritocracy, 1974 (Box 8)
    - Methodology, 1962-1965 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous essays, 1980, 1985, undated (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous radicalism, 1969, undated (Box 8)
    - The new American system of political economy, 1989 (Box 8)
    - New Left conference, 1973-1974 (Box 8)
    - New Left ideology, 1971-1973 (Box 8)
    - On Malthusian economics, 1979 (Box 8)
    - Poetry, pushpin, utility, 1975, undated, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Psychiatric issues, 1953, 1962-1967 (Box 8)
    - Quesnayan algebra, 1986, undated (Box 8)
    - Radical political economy, 1968-1971, undated, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Reagonomics, 1981, undated, 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Revival of rationing/economic stagnation, 1964-1969, undated (Box 9)
    - Revolutions in economic thought, 1966-1970 (Box 9)
    - Roosevelt on economic humanism and market socialism, 1969-1971 (Box 9)
    - Schumpeter, 1980 (Box 9)
    - Short essays, miscellaneous topics, 1980-1981, undated (Box 9)
    - Socialist designs, 1977 (Box 9)
    - Social responsibility of business/ugly corporate America (Box 9)
    - Statistical anti-semitism, Jewish and Gentile, 1966, undated (Box 9)
    - Student indiscipline, 1968-1970, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Technological change, 1966, undated (Box 9)
    - Tenure, 1971-1976 (Box 9)
    - U.S. economic ideology, 1957-1958, 1977, undated (Box 9)
    - Vicissitudes of Marxian economics, 1970 (Box 10)
    - Welfare state, 1975-1976 (Box 10)
    - What the radical economists are saying, 1973, undated (Box 10)
    - Why Johnny can't think straight, 1982, undated (Box 10)
  - Income Distribution Subseries, 1940s-1980s, 2 boxes
    Bronfenbrenner's interest and research in income distribution spanned his entire professional career. Folders contain notes, speeches, drafts and publications written by Bronfenbrenner, papers written by others, correspondence, clippings, and other miscellaneous documents. Arranged alphabetically by original folder title.
    - Alternative approaches, 1970s, 1980s, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - American inequality, 1970s, 1980s (Box 10)
    - Automation, 1964 (Box 10)
    - Corrections on income distribution theory, 1960s, 1970s, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Economic growth, 1959 (Box 10)
    - Ethical issues, 1960s, 1970s, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Ethics and justice, 1970s (Box 11)
    - Foreign distributions, 1960s (Box 11)
    - Growth rates of income and wealth, 1960s (Box 11)
    - Guidelines and guideposts, 1960s (Box 11)
    - Heterodox approaches to income distribution, undated (Box 11)
    - Incidence of collective bargaining, 1973 (Box 11)
    - Kyoto data, 1980 (Box 11)
    - Lydall book (Box 11)
    - Methodology, 1940s, 1950s (Box 11)
    - Microeconomic issues, 1960s, 1970s (Box 11)
    - Neoclassical macro distribution theory, 1960s (Box 11)
    - Other topics on distribution, 1970s (Box 11)
    - Poverty, 1980s (Box 11)
    - Production functions, 1960s, 1970s (Box 11)
    - Stieglitz paper, 1968 (Box 11)
    - Technological progress, 1966-1967 (Box 11)
    - Ten issues on distribution theory, 1970s (Box 11)
    - U.S. income distribution, 1940s, 1960s (Box 11)
    - Wages and employment, 1968 (Box 11)
    - Wage differentials, 1970s (Box 11)
  - Japan Material Subseries, 1940s-1990s and undated
    After the Second World War, Bronfenbrenner played an important consultative role in economic relations between the U.S. and Japan. His work and research on the Japanese economy during this period and in subsequent years cover almost all relevant economic issues, with emphasis on development economics, banking, and trade. The series also houses a published collection of short stories regarding his experience in Japan. Formats include research notes, speeches, writings by Bronfenbrenner, papers written by other authors relevant to his research, correspondence, newspaper articles, and other items. The folders are ordered alphabetically by original title.
    - Academics in Japan, 1974-1977 (Box 12)
    - Banking system, 1969 (Box 12)
    - Class notes (Box 12)
    - Conferences, 1961-1963 (Box 12)
    - Consumer sovereignty, 1989 (Box 12)
    - Development economics, 1960s (Box 12)
    - Economic aspects of occupation, 1960s and 1970s, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Economic growth, 1960s and 1974, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Economic history of occupation, 1970s (Box 13)
    - Economic thought, 1955, 1967-1968 (Box 13)
    - Education, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Galbrathian economy, 1970 (Box 13)
    - Growth and recession, 1990s (Box 13)
    - Harry Johnson memorial lecture, 1978 (Box 13)
    - History of Japan, 1989 (Box 13)
    - Income distribution, 1960s (Box 13)
    - Industrial revolution, 1968-1969 (Box 13)
    - Japan Foundation, 1970s (Box 13)
    - Japanese universities, 1960s (Box 13)
    - Kanji vs Romaji, 1956 and 1977 (Box 13)
    - Kato-Kyoso (excessive competition), 1960s (Box 13)
    - Kenan Foundation, 1982-1984 (Box 14)
    - Labor economics, 1970s (Box 14)
    - Lessons of Japanese development, 1986 (Box 14)
    - Letters, 1980s (Box 14)
    - Lockheed in Japan, 1976-1977 (Box 14)
    - Locomotive theory, 1978-1979 (Box 14)
    - Loose materials on Japanese economy and economics (Box 14)
    - Management (Box 14)
    - Meiji Era, 1959 and 1960s (Box 14)
    - Modern Japan, 1979-1980 (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 14)
    - News from Japan, 1980s (Box 14)
    - Newspaper articles, 1980s and 1990s (Box 14)
    - NIEO proposals/debt problem, 1980s (Box 14)
    - Notes (Box 14)
    - Occupation economics, 1960s (Box 14)
    - Occupation of Japan, 1978-1979, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Open economy macroeconomics, 1980s (Box 15)
    - Post-war recovery, 1940s (Box 15)
    - Professor Takata, 1980 (Box 15)
    - Productivity, 1981 (Box 15)
    - Prospects of Japanese democracy, 1955 (Box 15)
    - Radharaman Prasad Sinha C.V. (Box 15)
    - Recession, 1970s (Box 15)
    - Relations between U.S. and Japan, 1970s (Box 15)
    - Shimomura controversy (Japan Development Bank), 1960s (Box 15)
    - Short stories, 1978 (Box 15)
    - System of economic education, 1963 (Box 15)
    - Taxation, 1949 (Box 15)
    - Tomioka Stories from Occupied Japan (Box 15)
    - Trade notes and leaflets, 1950s-1970s (Box 15)
    - Trade council, 1960s and 1970s, 1 of 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Trade council, 1960s and 1970s, 2 of 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Trade creation, undated (Box 16)
    - Trade U.S.-Japan and letters, 1971 (Box 16)
    - Trickle-down, 1980-1981 (Box 16)
    - U.S.-Japan trade relations, 1961-1975 (Box 16)
    - Value-added tax/Shoup visit, 1988 (Box 16)
    - War bride's problem, 1950s (Box 16)
    - Waseda university centennial, 1982 (Box 16)
    - Welfare state, undated (Box 16)
    - Trade creation, undated (Box 16)
    - Western economy transported on Japan, 1983 (Box 16)
  - Orthodox Topics Subseries, 1950s-1994 and undated
    Topics covered include macroeconomics, especially in U.S. monetary economics, international trade and economic growth theory. Formats include notes, speeches, drafts and other writings, papers written by other economicsts on topics relevant to Bronfenbrenner's research, correspondence relevant to the subject, clippings and articles, and other miscellaneous documents. Arranged alphabetically by original folder title.
    - Aggregate wage theory, 1978-1980 (Box 17)
    - Baumol and Lovell papers, 1960s (Box 17)
    - Brain drain, 1960s (Box 17)
    - Business responsibility, 1970s (Box 17)
    - Chicago School, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Cliometrics, 1977 (Box 17)
    - Clinton health plans, 1994 (Box 17)
    - Commission on money and credit, 1960s (Box 17)
    - Cost-push inflation, 1974 (Box 17)
    - Crash of 1929, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Currency choice defense, 1979-1980 (Box 17)
    - Davidson on Keynes on money, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Demand for money, 1960s, 1 of 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Demand for money, 1960s, 2 of 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Econometrics, 1950s (Box 18)
    - Economic controls, 1976 (Box 18)
    - The economist's "ABC for reflation", 1986 (Box 18)
    - Elasticity and absorption: approaches in international macroeconomics, 1975 (Box 18)
    - Elasticity version of the equation of exchange, 1970s (Box 18)
    - Encyclopedia of Social Sciences: Inflation, 1961-1963 (Box 18)
    - Essays, 1989 (Box 18)
    - Free trade, protection and international income equality, 1977 (Box 18)
    - Friedman vs Keynes, 1966 (Box 18)
    - Friedman-Mieselman controversy, 1965-1966 (Box 18)
    - Frey's dilemma, 1974 (Box 18)
    - Hoarding on the wing, 1988 (Box 18)
    - Indexation, 1978-1979 (Box 18)
    - Inflation, 1970 (Box 18)
    - Inflation persistence (Box 18)
    - Inflation and stagflation (to encyclopedia), 1983 (Box 18)
    - International competitiveness and the U.S. dollar, 1985-1987 (Box 19)
    - International macroeconomics, 1970 (Box 19)
    - International trade, 1965 (Box 19)
    - Japanese productivity, 1982 (Box 19)
    - Joint economic committee, 1969 (Box 19)
    - Keynesian employment function, 1976 (Box 19)
    - Korea and the Yen-Dollar rate, 1990 (Box 19)
    - "Let-'er-Rip" inflation policies, 1971 (Box 19)
    - Labor-supply, 1965-1966 (Box 19)
    - Land taxation, 1969 (Box 19)
    - Liquidity functions, 1959 (Box 19)
    - Macroeconomics textbook draft, 1970-1974, 1 of 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Macroeconomics textbook draft, 1971-1974, 2 of 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Marginalism in labor economics (Box 19)
    - Microeconomics of inflation, 1978-1979 (Box 19)
    - Monetary rules, 1960s (Box 20)
    - Monetary statistics of the U.S. (Box 20)
    - Multiplier theory, 1961 (Box 20)
    - On dumping gold, 1979 (Box 20)
    - OPEC, 1980s (Box 20)
    - Phillips curve reconsidered (Box 20)
    - Poverty, 1960s and 1970s (Box 20)
    - Private savings, 1960s, 1 of 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Private savings, 1981, 2 of 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Profit theory, 1950s and 1960s (Box 20)
    - Public appropriations, 1965 (Box 20)
    - Scarcity hypothesis, 1968 and 1970 (Box 20)
    - Sensitivity analysis for econometricians, 1972 (Box 20)
    - Statistical refinements of the inflation concept, 1965 (Box 20)
    - Square root rule, 1960s (Box 20)
    - Sraffa controversy, 1974 (Box 20)
    - Stagflation, 1970, 1 of 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Stagflation, 1974, 2 of 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Stagflation theory, 1976 (Box 20)
    - Theory of employment, 1986 (Box 20)
    - Walras's law, 1990 (Box 20)
    - Wisconsin, 1985 (Box 20)
  - People Subseries, 1949-1993 and undated, 2 boxes
    Following Bronfenbrenner's own filing system, this research-related subseries contains folders labelled with individuals' names, most of them notable economists, in whose research Bronfenbrenner was interested or with whom he corresponded, or both. There are also two "Miscellaneous" folders. The folders contain a mix of materials: correspondence between Bronfenbrenner and the economist named on the folder, annotated and unmarked articles, and papers by Bronfenbrenner or by others. There are two folders of materials concerning Kei Shibata, who during the 1930s wrote on Marxian economics and equilibrium balance. Arranged in alphabetical order by last name.
    - Adelman, M., 1949-1953 (Box 21)
    - Baumol, W., 1982 (Box 21)
    - Davidson, P., 1979 (Box 21)
    - De Fremeny [Fremery?], 1971-1976 (Box 21)
    - Ferguson, C., 1971 (Box 21)
    - Fitzgerald, B., 1971, 1975, undated (Box 21)
    - Friedman, M., 1952, 1971-1975 (Box 21)
    - Gross, E., 1976 (Box 21)
    - Frisch, H., 1963-1979 (Box 21)
    - Galloway, L., undated (Box 21)
    - Hamilton, E., 1975 (Box 21)
    - Hollander, S., 1983, 1988 (Box 21)
    - Hollister, R., 1978 (Box 21)
    - Kaldor, N., 1958 (Box 21)
    - Keesing, D., 1966 (Box 21)
    - Leijonhufvud, A., 1974 (Box 21)
    - Lerner, A., 1982 (Box 21)
    - Mayer, T., 1965 (Box 21)
    - Means, G., 1975 (Box 21)
    - Meltzer, A., 1968, 1993 (Box 21)
    - Minsky, H., 1980 (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous professional correspondence, 1955-1992, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Oshima, H., 1967 (Box 22)
    - Rhomberg, R., 1968 (Box 22)
    - Rothschild, K., 1964, undated (Box 22)
    - Samuelson, P., 1980, undated (Box 22)
    - Sato, R., 1966 (Box 22)
    - Warburton, C., 1951 (Box 22)
    - Sherman, H., 1966 (Box 22)
    - Shibata, K., 1962-1968, undated, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Slichter, S., 1958 (Box 22)
    - Smith, V., 1964 (Box 22)
    - Solow, R., 1972 (Box 22)
    - Spengler, J., 1974 (Box 22)
    - Stein, H., 1982, undated (Box 22)
    - Sweezy, P., 1968 (Box 22)
    - Tullock, G., 1976-1977 (Box 22)
    - Viner, J., 1969 (Box 22)
    - Williams, J., 1974 (Box 22)
    - Yasuba, Y., 1980, undated (Box 22)